Register of the National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies Records, 1939-1946
Hoover Institution Archives
- COUNTRIES FILE, 1933-1948
  - Greece, 1941-1945
    - Subject file
      - Greek War Relief Association, Inc. (Folder 7)
      - Near East Foundation (Folder 8)
  - Haiti, 1941. Miscellany (Box 152., Folder 1)
  - Hungary, 1939-1941
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 2)
    - Printed matter. Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. News Bulletin (Folder 3)
  - India, 1942-1943. Miscellany (Folder 4)
  - Ireland, 1941. Clippings (Folder 5)
  - Italy, 1940-1945. Clippings (Folder 6)
  - Latvia, 1939-1940. Printed matter. Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. News Bulletin (Folder 7)
  - Lithuania, 1941-1945
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 8)
    - Printed matter. Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. News Bulletin (Folder 9)
  - Luxemburg, 1940-1941. Miscellaneous material including correspondence of National Committee (Folder 10)
  - Netherlands, 1941-1945
    - Clippings (Folder 11-12)
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee
      - General. Miscellaneous material including correspondence with the Queen Wilhelmina Fund (Box 153., Folder 1-2)
      - Loon, Henrik Van (Folder 3)
      - Stolk, Cornelius Van (Folder 4)
    - Subject file. The Queen Wilhelmina Fund (Folder 5)
  - Norway, 1940-1943
    - Clippings and typescript excerpts from newspapers (Folder 6)
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 7-8)
    - Memoranda, reports and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Box 154., Folder 1-3)
    - Printed matter. Miscellaneous publicity (Folder 4)
    - Speeches and writings. Evang, Karl, "Norway's Food in Peace and War" (Folder 5)
  - Poland. Mostly material relating to the Commission for Polish Relief, Inc.
    - Clippings and typescript excerpts from newspapers (Box 155., Folder 1)
    - Log of Commission representatives in Germany, prepared by Columba Murray (Folder 2)
    - Map indicating areas of service by Commission for Polish Relief in Romania (Folder 3)
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee
      - General
        - General (Folder 4-8)
        - General (Box 156., Folder 1-2)
        - Letterheads used by Committee in Berlin (Folder 3)
      - British representatives (Folder 4)
      - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 5)
      - Majewski, Tomasz (Folder 6)
      - Strakacz, Sylwin, Consul General of Poland (Folder 7)
      - Znamiecki, Alexander, Relief Delegate of the Polish Government (Folder 8)
      - Zoltowsky, Janucz, Polish Financial Counselor (Folder 9)
    - Publications - News Bulletin, nos. 1-6 (Folder 10)
    - Report. Osinski, Henry, "Report on Organization and Operation of Mission in Poland, Dec. 1945 - Jan. 1947" (Box 157., Folder 1)
    - Statement of purpose and orgnization. Typescript draft (Folder 2)
    - Subject file
      - Jewish population in Poland. Miscellaneous material including clippings and correspondence (Folder 3)
      - Polish-American organizations (Folder 4)
      - Polish gold in Romania (Folder 5)
      - Transfer of contributions to Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. (Folder 6)
  - Portugal, 1941. Correspondence (Box 158., Folder 1)
  - Romania, 1939-1940. Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. News Bulletin and miscellany (Folder 2)
  - Scandinavia, 1941-1944. Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 3)
  - South America, 1941. Miscellany (Folder 4)
  - Soviet Union, 1940-1947
    - Clippings (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - Soviet Union. Posol'stvo (United States) (Folder 6)
      - Russian War Relief, Inc. (Folder 7)
      - Straight, John(?) (Folder 8)
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 9)
  - Spain, 1940-1945
    - Clippings (Folder 10)
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 11)
  - Sweden, 1941-1945
    - Clippings and typescript exerpts of newspapers (Folder 12)
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 13)
  - Switzerland, 1940-1942
    - Clippings (Folder 14)
    - Correspondence (Folder 15)
  - Yugoslavia, 1940-1944
    - Clippings (Folder 16)
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 17)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1932-1948.
  Includes correspondence, reports and printed matter
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science (Box 159., Folder 1)
  - American Business Survey (Folder 2)
  - American Legion (Folder 3)
  - American organizations. Miscellaneous (Folder 4)
  - Bishop's Fund for World Relief (Folder 5)
  - Bonus Marchers in 1932 (Folder 6)
  - Book lists (Folder 7)
  - Boy Scouts of America (Folder 8)
  - Capitol Gist Service (Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Hall Meeting (Folder 10)
  - Cartoons (Folder 11)
  - Child Welfare League of America (Folder 12)
  - Children of Europe (Folder 13)
  - Citizens for Victory (Folder 14)
  - Clothing (Folder 15)
  - Committe of Americans to Keep America American (Box 160., Folder 1)
  - Committee of Mercy, War Relief Clearing House (Folder 2)
  - Committees - Miscellaneous (Folder 3)
  - Council for Democracy (Folder 4)
  - Democracies Allied Relief (Folder 5)
  - Easter Food for Europe Pilgrimage (Folder 6)
  - Facing the Facts (Folder 7)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Sayre, John (Folder 9)
    - Smucker, Don (Folder 10)
  - Fight for Freedom Committee (Folder 11)
  - Foreign Relief Appeal (Folder 12)
  - Foster Parents Plan for War Children (Folder 13)
  - Friends of Democracy (Folder 14)
  - Food
    - Maps (Folder 15)
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence (Box 161., Folder 1-2)
    - Printed matter
      - General
        - General (Folder 3-4)
        - Black, John, "Food Enough." Typescript draft (Folder 5)
      - Clippings and typescript extracts from newspapers
        - General
          - 1940-1941 (Box 162., Folder 1-3)
          - 1944-1945 (Folder 4-5)
        - New York Times (Folder 6)
  - Foreign funds (Box 163., Folder 1)
  - Foreign holdings of U.S. properties (Folder 2)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Folder 3)
  - Freemasonry - United States (Folder 4)
  - Gallup poll (Folder 5)
  - Health conditions of the civilian population in Europe
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Influenza (Folder 7)
    - Tuberculosis (Folder 8)
    - Typhus (Folder 9)
  - Help the Children Committee (Folder 10)
  - Horace Mann League (Folder 11)
  - Human Events (Folder 12)
  - Infant mortality in Europe (Folder 13)
  - International Labor Office (Folder 14)
  - International Committee of the Red Cross
    - Memoranda, correspondence, and reports
      - General (Folder 15)
      - Sparrow, Edward (Folder 16)
    - Printed matter
      - General (Folder 17)
      - Clippings (Folder 18)
  - Keep America Out of War Congress (Box 164., Folder 1)
  - Kits for Europe's Children (Folder 2)
  - Kiwanis International (Folder 3)
  - Legion for American Unity (Folder 4)
  - Loyal Americans of German Descent (Folder 5)
  - Loyalty for Victory (Folder 6)
  - Medical supplies (Folder 7)
  - No Foreign War Committee (Folder 8)
  - Mothers of American Sons (Folder 9)
  - Post-War World Council (Folder 10)
  - President's Committee on War Relief Agencies (Folder 11)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1941
    - Clippings (Folder 12)
    - Correspondence (Folder 13)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin, 1940-1941. Correspondence
    - Incoming (Folder 14)
    - Outgoing (Folder 15)
  - Russian War Relief, Inc. (Folder 16)
  - Save the Children Federation (Folder 17)
  - Shipping
    - General (Folder 18)
    - Mercy ships (Folder 19)
    - Frese, H., "Ships for Relief" (Folder 20)
  - To Stop European Wars Forever Council (Box 165., Folder 1)
  - U.S. Committee for the Care of European Children (Folder 2)
  - Union for Democratic Action (Folder 3)
  - United Fund for Refugee Children, Inc. (Folder 4)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (Folder 5)
  - United Service Organization (U.S.O.) (Folder 6)
  - United States. Department of State. Correspondence and other material, 1939-1944
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Hull, Cordell. Includes clippings (Folder 8)
  - United States. Department of the Treasury (Folder 9)
  - Vitamins (Folder 10)
  - Young Men's Christian associations (Folder 11)
- MEMORABILIA, n.d.
  - One blue and white lapel pin inscribed, "Greek War Relief - I Helped" (Box 166.)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1938?-1941?
  - 5 prints depicting Howard Kershner (Box A)
  - 6 prints depicting prominent women including Dorothy Dunbar Bromley, Geraldine Farrar, Margaret E. Sanger, and Faith Baldwin (Box B)
  - 6 prints depicting Herbert Hoover's 1938 trip to Finland (Box C)
  - 1 print depicting bound volumes, Resolutions of Endorsement Approving the Plan of National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies (Box D)
  - 46 prints depicting scenes in Norway after the German invasion (Box E)
  - 10 postcards entitled "Miseres de l'hiver 1940-1941," depicting scenes of Belgium in the winter of 1940-1941 (Box F)